Lots of love!
What? You little mutt!
- Come back here!
- Oh!
Bring back my gyros!
Hey, watch it!
Excuse me.
Pardon me. Whoa!
- Hey! Bone-headed pooch!
- Sorry!
Ruh-roh!
Dispatch, I've got a stray dog
on a tube of compressed meat.
Repeat. I have
a grand theft gyro in progress.
Hey, slow it down!
Huh?
Yikes. Whoa!
Hey!
Zoinks!
Like, slow down, dude.
♪ Show me
the meaning of being lonely ♪
♪ One is the loneliest number ♪
♪ Lonely ♪
♪ I'm Mr. Lonely ♪
Hello, I'm Ira Glass.
Welcome to another episode
of my new podcast,
Friends, Who Needs Them?
You Do.
This week's challenge,
put yourself out there.
When the hand of friendship
is offered to you, take it.
You can do it.
Now, go. Make some friends.
Excuse me!
Coming through!
Dude!
Whew!
Huh?
Make friends. Check.
Nice to meet you,
Shelly and Sandy.
How was your day?
Oh, you want me to start?
How polite, Sandy.
Well, I told my mom I was
meeting my pals at the beach.
So, if she asks,
this technically counts
as a playdate.
But it's all good.
I like eating lunch by myself.
And hanging out by myself.
And playing ping-pong
by myself.
I lose a lot of balls.
Ahh!
I gotta warn you,
it's got gummy worms,
tater tots,
and ketchup leather.
Hmm.
I know. No liverwurst.
It's not like me
to forget the protein.
Yeah, I get it.
Nobody likes my sandwiches.
Whoa!
Mm. Is that peppercorn?
Sand.
- There you are!
- Ahh!
This mangy stray's
done enough damage for today.
He's coming with me.
He's not a stray.
Is he your dog?
He is, like, totally mine.
If you wanna be.
I'd like that very much.
Okay, then. What's his name?
I don't have one.
His name's...
- Snacks.
- What?
Snacks?
Uh, I mean... Scooby!
Middle name?
Dooby?
Last name.
Doo.
All right.
If the dog has a middle name,
there's no punishment
for damages or theft.
I don't like it,
but them's the laws.
Well, have a good day, sir.
Mr. Dooby-Doo.
I'm Norville,
but everyone calls me Shaggy.
Raggy.
No, it's Shaggy.
That's what I said. Raggy.
We'll work on it.
Shaggy, you and your
new friend better hurry up
if you want to trick-or-treat.
Yay! Okay, Mom.
Let me show you my room.
I mean, our room.
Who's that?
This is Blue Falcon.
He's half-man, half-falcon.
Well, mostly man. All man.
I guess it's just the suit
that's falcon.
And his wonder dog sidekick,
Dynomutt.
Like, they solve crimes
and save the world together.
Cool.
Ooh!
What's this?
- It's a bed. You sleep in it.
- Huh.
Soft. I've never had
a bed before.
In fact, I've never had
anything before.
I, uh...
I ran out this afternoon
and I got something for you.
I know we just met
and I didn't wanna
seem too desperate
or, you know,
come on too strong, but...
I love it.
I promise
I'll never take it off.
Thanks.
Thank you!
Trick or treat!
I love Halloween!
And may I say,
you sure look good
in that costume.
Ranks, Raggy.
It's all in the hips.
Whoa! Jackpot!
Big house, big candy.
Like, no way, bro.
That's the Rigby house.
It's haunted.
Let's get outta here!
Mine!
Hey!
Give it back!
Yeah! We worked hard
for that free candy.
This stuff will rot your teeth.
Yeah. Don't you know Halloween
is just a marketing ploy
by Big Corn Syrup?
Yeah, we're okay with that.
Ruh-roh.
Your blood sugar
will thank us.
Are you guys all right?
Yeah.
They just hurt my pride.
And my tail feathers.
Let me give you a hand.
I'm Fred.
- This is Velma.
- Hi.
- And that's Daphne.
- Hey.
I'm Shaggy.
And this is Scooby-Doo.
Nice to meet you.
Cool Wonder Woman costume.
And are you... Harry Potter?
I'm Ruth Bader Ginsburg,
obviously.
Which house is she in?
Hufflepuff?
She's a Supreme Court justice.
Oh. Slytherin.
Come on.
Let's go get your candy back.
Wait,
that's the Rigby house.
It's haunted by a ghost.
Ghost?
Ghost or no ghost,
it's Halloween.
No one should go home
without their candy.
Uh... Okay.
We'll go in the haunted house
this one time,
but we're not gonna make
a habit out of this.
Right, Scoob?
Right.
Hello?
Anybody home?
This living room feels more
like a dying room.
Here you go, Shaggy.
Great.
Thanks a bunch. Let's go.
It's the ghost!
Guys, there's no such thing
as ghosts.
Hmm.
Uh...
Girl dressed like Judge Judy,
I don't think
this is a good idea.
Huh?
- The ghost!
- Go get help!
Aah!
Come on, hurry!
Guys, we gotta do something.
- Quick, upstairs!
- Come on, let's go!
Daphne!
Whoa!
Run, Daphne, run!
Fred, look!
Uh-oh.
Velma!
Got it.
Hey! What are you... Oh.
Oh.
Huh?
Gotcha.
Jeepers.
It's a Halloween mask.
Mr. Rigby!
Uh, guys?
I think we just found
the world's smallest Walmart.
Man, this guy
stole a lot of stuff!
Bag it all up, Frank.
He's going away
for a long time.
I would've
gotten away with this
if it weren't for you
meddling...
Congratulations, everyone.
We just proved
this house wasn't haunted,
and busted a perp.
And even better,
we got our candy back.
Not bad for a bunch of kids.
Maybe we should do this again.
- I like it.
- I'm in.
What do you say, guys?
We're in.
I mean, like, how many
scary monsters could there be?
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo ♪
♪ Where are you? ♪
♪ We got some work to do now ♪
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo
Where are you? ♪
♪ We need some help
From you now ♪
♪ Come on, Scooby-Doo
I see you ♪
♪ Pretending you Got a sliver ♪
♪ But you're not fooling me
'Cause I can see ♪
♪ The way you Shake and shiver ♪
♪ You know we got
A mystery to solve ♪
♪ So, Scooby-Doo
Be ready for your act ♪
♪ Don't hold back ♪
♪ And, Scooby-Doo
If you come through ♪
♪ You're gonna have yourself
A Scooby Snack ♪
♪ That's a fact! ♪
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo
Here are you ♪
♪ You're ready
And you're willin' ♪
♪ If we can count on you
Scooby-Doo ♪
♪ I know
We'll catch that villain ♪
All right, everybody.
I would like to pose to you all
the question of questions.
What's next for Mystery Inc.?
Ooh, I totally have
the answer. Lunch.
No, Shaggy, I think
what Fred means is that...
I was also gonna say lunch.
Guys, guys, guys.
The Mystery Machine
needs a whole new...
Needs a whole new everything,
and I'm never gonna
get that smell out.
I told you I needed a walk.
It's time to turn Mystery Inc.
into a real business.
What do you mean?
Like, carry a briefcase,
and wear a tie, and pay taxes?
Wait, have you not been
paying your taxes?
I handle our accounting.
Look, we're ready
to take on bigger cases,
scarier villains,
and creepier mysteries,
but that takes money.
Fortunately,
we found a possible investor.
Oh, whoopee, a diner.
I'll have a napkin
and some hand sanitizer.
Whoa, man! It's Simon Cowell.
♪ In the shallow ♪
♪ I'm off the deep end
Watch as I dive in ♪
Uh, congratulations, gentlemen.
You are terrible.
How does he do that?
See, he's mean,
but he makes it fun.
We appreciate your interest
in Mystery Inc., Mr. Cowell.
Every successful group
requires hard work
and determination.
Identifying potential is what
I do, and you have got it.
Fred, you're the tank.
The muscle.
- Cool.
- Daphne is
the people person. The empath.
- Aw.
- And Velma's got the smarts
- and technical savvy.
- Thanks.
But you two
aren't even listening.
You're eating a clownishly
oversized sandwich.
Like, sorry, man.
You lost us at,
"Hard work and determination."
But you got us back
at "sandwich."
Look, a group can only be as
strong as its weakest links.
Bottom line, I can't invest
with these two involved.
But, Mr. Cowell, Shaggy and
Scooby are our best friends.
Yeah, and like, what's more
valuable than friendship?
Literally, anything.
You can't count on friendship.
People change.
And when you get
into real trouble,
friendship won't save the day.
Like, we don't need this,
Scoob. Let's bounce.
Yeah, we know
when we're not wanted.
No.
- Ugh. Wait.
- Come on, guys.
He didn't mean it.
No fries for you. Hmm!
You believe
the nerve of that dude?
Simon Cowell thinks friendship
won't save the day.
What does he know?
Yeah, he's not that smart.
Just sounds like it,
because he's British.
Good point, Raggy.
As long as we have each other,
we'll be just fine on our own.
Right.
Yes!
Eyes?
Raggy, look.
- Huh?
- The pin. It has eyes.
Oh, Scoob,
I know it feels like
everyone's judging us today.
Even the bowling pins.
But don't freak out on me, bud.
Uh...
What's the hold-up?
The ball return
won't return our ball.
Huh.
Oh, there it is.
Zoinks!
Like, what is going on?
What are those things?
I don't know,
but they don't look friendly.
No offense, but I think
I liked you better
as a bowling ball.
Me, too.
Look out!
Whoa!
No running.
They're coming.
- What now?
- Follow my lead.
Who's hungry?
Check out the specials.
So, like, what are you guys
in the mood to eat?
And please don't say human.
Or dog.
Okay, Bowling Alley Yakitori.
And how about you guys?
Hot wings to share?
Uh-huh.
Got it. And for you?
Oh, no! We're out of calamari.
This way, Scoob!
Huh, I always wondered
what was back here.
Underwhelming.
All units.
Attention, all units.
We have a 4-1-5 in progress
at the Takamoto Bowl.
"Tiny violent
shape-shifting robots
chasing a man and a dog
in a bowling alley,
linen store or car wash."
Wow, the police really do have
a code for everything.
The Takamoto Bowl?
That's where
Scoob and Shaggy hang out.
Oh, no.
Let's go.
Did we lose 'em?
Pretty sure we didn't.
Yikes!
Looks like this is goodbye,
old buddy.
We never saw Paris.
Huh?
Oh, man,
dig that crazy elevator.
You okay, Scooby-Doo?
Yeah. I'm good.
Whew. Where are we?
Dude, hang on.
Do you realize where we are?
- No.
- Look around, man.
The clean, modern aesthetic.
The cool blue color palette.
- We're in...
- IKEA!
...the Falcon Fury!
Did you say IKEA?
Nope. I said Falcon Fury.
Just like you.
Gentlemen, welcome aboard.
I'm Dee Dee Skyes,
pilot of the Falcon Fury.
- Well, we're Scoob...
- Scooby and Shaggy.
We know. Follow me.
Who sent those robots?
It's this guy named
Dick Dastardly.
Shocker!
He's a psychotic supervillain.
He's trying to
you.
Scoob, somebody thinks we're
important enough to...
It's nice to be wanted.
Mm, I hear that.
Oh, wow!
- Look! Look!
- Wow.
Yes, I know
it's super cool in here,
and I would totally let you
guys press random buttons,
but they told me
we need to move.
Seriously?
We're doing this now?
Ooh. Is it him? Is it him?
Yep. He likes to make
an entrance.
Ladies and gentlemen,
since the dawn of time...
...the falcon
has been worshipped
as a symbol
of freedom and victory.
Now,
a new kind of falcon
rules the sky.
And he is one bad mamma jamma.
Blue Falcon!
Ooh, yeah!
Welcome to the Falcon Fury.
Hang on, hang on.
Turn on the lights.
Where are my balloons, Dee Dee?
When I say "Falcon Fury,"
that's supposed
to cue the balloons.
Keith, what is the deal
up there, man?
I missed the cue.
Duh. You've got one job, pal.
Anyway,
welcome aboard,
I'm Blue Falcon.
No, you're not.
Yes, I am.
I told you I wasn't going to
be the only one who noticed.
No, Blue Falcon's suit
has a bigger red "F"
on the chest,
and it's way less, uh, scaly.
They're feathers, all right?
And it's called an upgrade.
This ain't
your daddy's Blue Falcon.
I think you mean this ain't
Allow me to introduce you
to Blue Falcon's
large adult son, Brian.
Dynomutt!
Oh, him you recognize?
Well, sure, man!
Dynomutt is the dog wonder.
Blue Falcon doesn't go
anywhere without him.
And yet here I am. Without him.
Ow! What was that for?
Making sure this isn't a dream.
You're supposed
to pinch yourself.
- Ow!
- Oh!
Ow.
Finished?
- Ow!
- Yes.
- Wait, Brian...
- Blue Falcon.
- If you're Blue Falcon now...
- I am.
- Does that mean...
- Yes.
Regretfully, my father has
moved on to a better place.
Oh, no!
What? Oh, no, he's not dead.
He retired to Palm Beach.
We still miss him
very, very, very,
- very, very...
- Oh, no, he's glitching.
No, I'm not. Let me finish.
...very, very, very much.
It's Dastardly.
He must have tracked you here
from the bowling alley.
Let's move it, people.
To the Falcon Nest.
Like, hey, wait up!
Nobody gets away
from Dick Dastardly.
Right, Rottens?
I need what's on that ship,
or I'll never get my treasure.
Do not fail me.
Dee Dee, take the helm.
Ready, sir.
You might want to buckle up.
And if you get sick,
puke on Brian.
Punch it, Dee Dee.
Hang on.
- Zoinks!
- What's this guy's deal?
Look, the hot goss
on my fan site
is that Dastardly's collecting
the three shells
of Seabiscuit...
It's skulls of Cerberus,
Brian. We went over this.
He's got one skull.
Our mission is to make sure
he doesn't get the other two.
Like, what do those creepy
skulls have to do with us?
No idea.
Hold tight.
- I can't shake him.
- Try the shake button.
Ooh, I'll take
a chocolate shake.
Vanilla, please.
- There is no shake button.
- Well, there should be.
All right, Rottens.
Launch the harpoons.
Incoming!
What is going on?
Well done. Reel them in.
Dynomutt, can you reverse the
polarity of the tractor beam?
Of course,
but that would make...
- Reverse on my mark.
- On it.
Now!
Why have we stopped pulling
in that ship?
Oh, no, no, no. No, no. No!
Argh! Drat!
Whew. Are you guys okay?
Yeah, but, like, if you want,
you can pull over
and drop us off here.
We'll walk home.
Dastardly could have
finished us if he wanted to.
I think he wants
you guys alive.
I knew you two were important.
It would be safer for you if
you joined us on our mission.
It would?
Ring, ring! Ring, ring!
Ring, ring!
Boop! Hello? Oh!
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Well, of course.
Uh, guys, adventure's calling,
and it's for you.
Hello, adventure.
Yes, will you take my name
and number off your list?
But, Raggy, this is our chance.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
We can show everyone
we're not the weak link.
Uh, Mr. Adventure, sir,
it's me again.
Uh, my partner is intrigued
by your offer,
but I'm still on the fence.
We're gonna have
to call you back. Bye-bye.
Click.
- You really wanna do this?
- Uh-huh.
Well, I'm not gonna
let you do it without me.
After all, there is no "I"
in Scooby and Shaggy.
Wait, is there?
No, all good.
We're in.
That's what I'm talking about!
Now, I've got a few waivers
for you guys to sign.
Oh, great. Great timing, Keith.
Thank you!
Well, uh,
the robots attacked
this talking dog
and a gangly dude
that had this habit
of using the word "like"
at the start of every sentence.
Almost as if he was
some middle-aged man's idea
of how a teenage hippie talks.
Oh, that's Scoob and Shaggy
all right.
So, what happened?
I don't know.
They seemed pretty bummed out.
I guess their friends
dumped them
in a cold-hearted way
or something.
And then this blue light
came down from the sky
and beamed them up.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Shaggy and Scooby were taken?
Yeah.
I'd have to assume that if
they were with their friends,
they wouldn't
have been kidnapped.,
I can't...
I can't breathe.
Whoever those friends are
must be carrying a ton of guilt
on their shoulders
right about now.
Okay, can you skip
the emotional punishment
and describe the robots,
please?
Yeah, sure. Uh, they looked
like what's in this box.
Whoa!
Guys,
this thing is increíble.
It's fully autonomous
and capable of modifying
its external appearance.
I'd like to shake the hand
of whoever created this.
And then, you know,
throw that hand in prison
for trying to kill our friends.
Right? Am I right?
Ew! Is that... a hair?
Maybe this can lead us
to our culprit.
What are you doing?
You're touching it
with bare fingers.
Grow up, Fred.
Do you know
how many stray hairs
the average human eats
every day without knowing it?
If it's more than zero,
I don't wanna know.
It's more. Much, much more.
Huh. Trace amounts
of mustache oil.
12-year-old Scotch.
Ugh. Is the bad guy my dad?
There are also some
microscopic soil particles.
Composition is a mix
of arsenic, selenium and...
Coppertone SPF 50.
Anything over 30 is a waste.
I'll see if the combination
of these elements
matches
a geographical location.
And...
Bingo. Dastardly Demolition.
Per county records,
last known owner is...
Dick Dastardly.
What would a creep like that
want with Scooby and Shaggy?
Hmm. Well, let's see what
the police department database
has to say.
Ooh. Quite a rap sheet.
It looks like
he's wanted for the theft
of archeological artifacts
from a dig in Peru.
Tatty bye.
That looks like
a giant dog skull.
Weird.
It gets weirder. He also stole
the genealogical records
of a dozen dogs
from the Global Kennel Club.
And apparently
he's been stealing Netflix
by using his mother's account.
That is not fair
for the rest of us
who have to pay for Netflix.
You have to pay for Netflix?
This will not stand.
Let's go get
that Dastardly dude.
I just needed you
to retrieve one simple canine,
so I could get my treasure.
Now, were the missions
a failure?
Pinhead.
The question was rhetorical.
Of course it was a failure
because you failed me.
You are responsible
for my suffering.
Oh, sorry. You're sorry?
You certainly are.
And I thought my last sidekick
was worthless.
At least he had a backbone.
And fur and a wet nose.
But you, whoa-ho-ho,
you've lowered the bar
to new depths
of craven ineptitude
I didn't even think
were possible.
That's not a compliment,
you aluminum imbecile!
You're not a partner,
you're a disgrace, a lemming,
a boot-licking...
...suck-up.
An example must be made.
I want you to know
this is going to hurt me
a lot more than
it's going to hurt you.
No, not really.
Let this be a lesson
to you all.
If you're going to be
a sniveling suck-face...
...you're going
to look the part.
Forget you mechanical morons.
I'll fetch the key myself.
To find the second skull,
I'm searching
every possible location
with high fossil density.
Brian! Quit putting filters
on your selfies
and get in the game.
Whoa, whoa,
what do you think I'm doing?
I'm putting my social media
feelers out there, Dynobutt.
Found it!
The second skull?
No. Even better.
The Falcon Fridge.
FYI, you are
officially out of...
everything.
Yes! I love these guys.
I'm busting my tail
to save the world for him,
and he loves the guys
who brought treats.
Prepare your taste buds
for a Scoob-Shag specialty.
Whoa, whoa. You put jalapeño
peppers on your ice cream?
Heat and sweet.
It's our signature dessert.
Heat signature!
That's it!
You guys are geniuses!
We're geniuses.
Take that, Simon Cowell.
The supernatural energy
in that skull
would give off
a specific heat signature.
All we gotta do
is locate that spot.
Boom! The skull
is in the Gobi Desert.
Incorrect.
I just found out
where the skull is,
and it's not
in the Gobi Desert.
It's in Romania.
Like, how do you know?
A hero never reveals
his secrets.
I believe you're thinking
of magicians.
I'm always thinking
But if you must know,
I got a DM from one of my fans
who gave me the locayshe.
Brian, those are a lot of words
no one your age
should be using.
Sir, this could be a trap
set by Dastardly.
If it was a trap, why would
Anonymous use his own name?
Wait, do you think "Anonymous"
is the name of a person?
Well, based on your tone
of voice, I don't any more.
Sir, we really should go
to the Gobi Desert.
I hear you.
You make a valid point,
but we're gonna do
my thing, okay?
To the Falcon Nest.
Brian, last time you listened
to someone on the Internet,
you thought Tinder was an app
that delivers firewood.
Velma, what do you got?
I built a sequencing program
to cross-match
the biographical data
that Dastardly stole
from the canine registry
against Scooby-Doo.
Good thing I'm the tank,
because I could
not do any of that.
Any leads?
All the dogs, and Scooby,
seem to be related.
Jeepers.
If I take Dastardly's work
and follow the trail...
Whoa! Scooby-Doo is the last
descendant of Peritas?
Who's Peritas?
He was
Alexander the Great's dog.
Okay, so, Scooby is related
to some ancient dog.
- So, what does that mean?
- I have no idea.
Guys, this is our
most important mystery ever.
Yeah. This isn't about
some guy in a rubber mask.
It's about one of us.
Fred, how much longer
to Dastardly Demolition?
I know a shortcut.
Hustle, you two!
We haven't got all day!
Second thoughts?
Honestly, buddy,
I'm on my 4th or 5th thoughts.
Oh, man.
This amusement park
isn't very amusing!
According to Anonymous,
the second skull
should be right here.
Hey! Did Dastardly get
the anonymous tip, too?
You dim-witted do-gooders!
I've already retrieved
the second skull
from the Gobi Desert.
Gobi Desert? Hmm. Where have I
heard that before?
Oh, right, me.
Okay, Brian,
we've had our differences,
but this is the moment
where we stand together and...
Run!
Classic Brian.
Dee Dee, you cover
Scooby and Shaggy.
I'll run interference.
Stop right there,
you filthy animal.
And your dog, too.
This way!
Aw.
Weak link, my butt.
Whoa, dude!
What do you want with us?
I don't care about you.
You're not remotely important.
It's the dog I need.
Raggy!
Stay! Sit! Heel!
Did nobody train this thing?
Oh, hey.
Look, I know it looks like
I'm hiding,
but this is actually
a superior vantage point!
Whoa!
Scooby-Dooby-Doo?
Where are you?
Come on now. Don't be scared.
I love dogs.
I had a dog myself once.
He was an ill-tempered brute
with a ghastly underbite,
who stunk and caused me
endless headaches.
He's lost now.
Is he chipped?
Forget about him.
It's all about you.
You, my friend, are special.
You see, within you lies a key.
What... I don't have your key.
No pockets.
No. You are the key.
Join me, Scooby-Doo,
and I will show you
how to harness your destiny
and become the most
important dog in the world.
No, thanks, Dastardly.
Oh, please.
My friends call me...
Dick.
Rokay, Rick.
No, I'm not a Rick.
I'm a Dick. With a D.
Rick. With a D.
D-D-D-Dick!
R-R-R-Rick.
Dick, Dick,
Dick!
Drat.
Brian! Do something!
- Like what?
- Like drop some F-bombs.
Hey, man, whoa,
let's keep it PG.
No. Falcon bombs!
You know, my utility belt
has so many little pouches.
- They're right there!
- Ah!
12 trillion volts, brother.
- You wanna throw it?
- Do I ever!
F-bombs away!
Here, boy! Where are you?
You're mine, Scooby-Doo!
Sit.
Good boy.
You can start screaming...
now.
Follow that dog.
- Brian!
- Raggy!
Whoo-hoo!
I hate the loops.
Give me that dog!
- Raggy!
- Scooby!
Everybody say,
"Hashtag foxy Falcon."
Hashtag foxy Falcon!
Drat!
Not again.
Dastardly will be back.
Please tell me
you got some leads.
Dastardly said I was the key.
- The key to what?
- Ah-ha!
- I knew this guy was special!
- Why?
Because the bad guy said so?
Exactly! What did Dastardly
say about you?
Well, I believe
his exact words were, uh,
"I don't care about you.
You're not remotely important."
And, "It's the dog I need."
Harsh.
And then he shot me
through the wall.
Really harsh.
But, on the bright side,
your friend is super important.
Now let's get
that dog a hero suit!
- Huh?
- Shouldn't we be focusing
on finding that third skull
before Dastardly?
Or why Scooby is so important?
- It could be a clue to...
- Details.
All right, first things first.
Come on, Scooby-Doo!
- Cool.
- Uh...
Right behind you, Scoob.
Drat, drat, and double drat!
What is it?
Scooby-Doo's friends.
How perfect.
Send me
their location immediately.
Oh!
Huh?
- Like, what's wrong?
- I don't know.
Oh, looks like
that old collar's in the way
of the chest panel.
Huh?
Hmm?
Whoa. Awesome!
What do you think, Raggy?
Looks great.
Hey.
Hey, man.
You're feeling left out.
I get it.
Totally natural
when two buddies realize
that one of them
is destined for greatness
and the other one
is destined for,
you know, other stuff.
Look, the point is,
I got you something, too.
Keith. Give it to me.
My Blue Falcon Confidence Pack.
Retails for $99.95.
You got your
Blue Falcon Nutrition Guide,
Blue Falcon resistance bands,
a copy of
my dad's autobiography,
No Falcon Around,
and my light-hearted follow-up,
Just Falcon Around.
Oh, thanks, man.
It means a lot
to hear that from you.
How do you mean?
Well, you know, we both
struggle with confidence.
When Dastardly attacked,
we were both freaking out
and hiding.
Hey! It was
a superior vantage point!
But, like, your father
was this great hero, right?
So, like, you're expected
to be one, too,
and those are big shoes
to fill.
I mean,
the pressure is monumental.
Not to mention
the imposter's syndrome
that comes with the territory.
How do you breathe
under the weight of all that?
Uh...
Dyno, what do you got?
The signal's too weak.
I can't lock in
the exact coordinates.
I'm gonna cross-check
the triangulation pattern.
Oh! Super cool.
Better than bowling, huh?
Hurry, Fred!
Shaggy and Scooby
are in trouble
and your shortcut
to Dastardly Demolition
is taking forever.
Technically, this route
is 73 meters longer
than the highway.
Meters, Velma?
I don't even know what that
means. What are we, in Europe?
It's a quantitatively superior
measurement system.
Get with the program, Fred.
Oh, you mean like your program?
"I'm Velma."
"The world is ones and zeros."
Maybe if you spent more
time reading books,
- then...
- Guys! Stop.
Why are we fighting?
We didn't eat lunch!
We're just hangry.
Ever since
Shag and Scoob disappeared,
there's been no one
to feed us
ridiculous sandwiches at lunch.
I miss them.
Oh, me, too. Those little
pickles on top are the best.
No! The guys,
not the sandwiches.
Aw, I miss them, too.
Ready?
Ready!
Okay, Shaggy,
take the picture.
Hurry up and take it.
This hurts my face.
Shaggy,
you have it on video.
Oops! Sorry.
Jinkies! Scooby and Shaggy
are with Blue Falcon?
Of course.
Blue light, beamed up.
That's the Falcon Fury.
How do you know so much
about superheroes
and so little
about the metric system?
Because I'm an American man.
Oh, I'm so happy they're okay.
Oh, no.
Pull over.
Oh, boy.
Okay, guys.
Let me do the talking.
I've seen Cops
at least six times.
So, I know exactly what to say.
Good evening, Officer...
Fred, say something!
Hi.
Do you kids have any idea
how fast you were going?
Was it, uh, too fast?
Funny story, Officer.
We were rushing
to capture this evil villain
who we thought was trying
to kill our friends.
Uh-huh.
Step out of the vehicle.
All of you.
You've gotta
believe us, Officer.
This guy is really dangerous.
Ooh, dangerous.
Sounds like he's a...
handsome guy.
Oh, no, no.
Bulbous nose. Huge chin.
Yeah, but in a cool way,
like Gérard Depardieu.
No, in a super gross way.
Like a rat and a mound
of hair had a baby.
How dare you!
Dick Dastardly!
I have so many mixed feelings.
How did you find us?
Oh, let's just say
I had insider information.
You have the right
to remain silent.
And everything you said
about my face...
...will be used against you
in a court of claw!
Ah.
Mm.
Does this make
my ears look big?
Makes your ego
look big.
What did you say?
I said, uh, fine.
You look, uh, fine.
It sounded like you said "ego."
Nope. Must be in your head.
- Hmm.
- Your giant, inflated head.
- What?
- Nothing.
Scooby! We need you!
As far as masks go,
I gotta say,
she was pretty hot.
Fred, focus.
We've got to find a way
to contact Scooby and Shaggy.
There goes the last bobby pin.
Daphne, what are you doing?
If Scooby and Shaggy were here,
they would accidentally sit
on a rigged chair,
or bump their heads
against a wall
and it would open
a secret passage out of here.
They are surprisingly
effective goofballs.
Whoa!
Ow.
Aw. Poor little thing.
Uh, Daph, he's not on our side.
Do you need help?
It's okay. I want to help you.
Better?
Aw, you're welcome.
Hey, hey.
Do you think you can help us
get out of here, little buddy?
Cool.
Now, reveal
the final skull to me.
Your reunion is nigh!
My heart's desire
is within reach!
Perfect. We have it!
Set a course
for Messick Mountain!
Messick Mountain?
We can't let him
get there first.
We have to warn Blue Falcon.
Huh? There's
a communications device.
I'm gonna see
if I can find a backdoor
into Blue Falcon's comms,
but I have no idea
what I'm patching into.
I've narrowed my search down
to 11 possible hot spots.
Oh. That one is a volcano.
Ten possible hot spots.
We need to search...
I suddenly feel funky.
- And I'm in.
- I've been hacked.
- Dynomutt!
- Emergency.
Blue Falcon, come in,
Blue Falcon!
I repeat, this is an emergency.
Stay out of
my search history.
My name is Velma Dinkley.
Who names their kid Velma?
We are
prisoners of Dick Dastardly!
Yikes! Where are you?
I don't know,
but we're heading towards
a place
called Messick Mountain.
That's close to
a possible third hot spot!
That's it!
The skull must be
beneath the mountain!
That was unpleasant.
Hello? Hello?
Where are Scooby and Shaggy?
- Hello? Hello?
- Whoa!
- We lost the signal.
- Velma?
Check it.
That's a lock. But to where?
The Gates to the Underworld.
It all makes sense now.
Oh, boy.
That's the serious face.
We always get in trouble
after that face.
Alexander the Great and
Peritas conquered the world
and built the gates to protect
their enormous treasure.
That's where the lock comes in.
Only Alexander or Peritas
can unlock it.
Or one of their descendants.
Dastardly's going to
use Scooby
to unlock the
Gates to the Underworld.
So what? What happens then?
Then all hell breaks loose.
Literally.
There's more than treasure
behind those gates.
Oh, jinkies.
What? I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Someone had to say it.
Look over there.
Whoa.
"Muttley."
Put that down!
You have no right
to be in here, Mystery Morons.
It's Mystery Inc.
Yeah, Fred. He knows.
Who is Muttley?
Muttley was my partner...
my criminal co-conspirator.
Until... Until...
I opened a portal,
a backdoor to the underworld.
And through it,
a glowing gold vision.
As I was about to enter,
Muttley insisted on taking
the risk himself.
Rasm-Frasm.
Ingrate.
I pleaded with him,
"Muttley,
please don't do this."
But no. The flatulent fleabag
wouldn't listen to reason.
Ta-da!
Good boy, Muttley. Bring it!
Yes, yes, come on.
But that ticket
was a one-way trip.
Muttley?
Even if I'd opened
a billion portals,
he could never come back.
- Uh-oh.
- Muttley!
Oh, no. No!
Get out of there!
Muttley! Muttley!
Because Muttley isn't the key.
Return them to their cell.
Please, Dastardly,
if you unlock those gates,
you'll...
Stop!
Poor man's Hemsworth
stays with me.
- No.
- How dare you?
Wait. Chris or Liam?
What are you doing with him?
Oh, I have grand plans
for Freddie boy.
I'm picking up
the skull signature.
Locking on.
These suits
are incredible, right?
Yeah!
Accentuates the good stuff,
hides the flaws.
I love it.
I wanna see
cheeks to seats, people.
Straps activated.
But my cheeks
still need a seat!
Here we go!
Shaggy, what are you doing?
Not so close.
We're about to get closer.
- Dee Dee, I advise we...
- Punch it!
Wow. The heat
from the geothermal vents
is creating
a completely unique ecosystem.
Which appears to be Mesozoic.
Just land the ship, Dee Dee!
Okay, Falcon Force.
Good luck.
Bring back that skull.
Scooby and I will stay
on the ship.
You know,
where it's safe and secure.
Dude, I'm pretty sure Scooby
is gonna be safest with us.
We're literally superheroes.
No, you don't get it.
We're chickens
and we always stick together,
so we're staying here.
Scoob?
Scoob's clearly important
to whatever Dastardly's
got planned. We need him.
Yeah. I'm the key.
The key? You're not the key.
You're my best friend.
At least I thought you were
until you whipped off
your collar.
My collar? You gave me the nod.
But I didn't think
you'd really do it.
Just come with us.
"Us"? You're an "us" now?
Well, what happened to us-us?
Raggy.
You need to choose.
Now, I'm staying on the ship.
Are you staying with me,
or going with them?
That's not fair.
Choose.
I never thought I'd say this,
but Simon Cowell was right.
You can't count on friendship.
You know what?
Simon Cowell is always right.
He gave the world
Kelly Clarkson.
I mean, how much proof
do you need?
Hey, man,
that breakup was brutal.
All right, Shaggy was totally
out of line.
We've never had
a fight before.
Brian!
Less talk, more walk!
See? I'm dealing with
the same thing with Dynobutt.
He's constantly riding me.
He expects me to be
just like my dad, and I'm not.
No, you're not.
All I need is a moment.
A hero moment.
To prove to him and the world
that I can do this.
Maybe we both do.
This thing still isn't working.
Dyno, what do you got?
I got bupkis.
Who needs your techno-malarkey
when we got this guy?
Now, let's let the real dog
sniff out this bone.
Got it!
Have fun being last!
What are you doing?
Huh. Raggy's never missed.
Hello!
Your tiny little brains
probably can't understand me.
So, I will speak slowly,
so that you may process
the welcoming tones
of my voice.
Uh, we understand
you perfectly.
Oh, word? No disrespect.
So, what brings you guys
to Mystery Island?
We're looking for a skull.
Yeah, it's about yea high,
and full of sharp,
pointy teeth.
You mean a slaghoople?
Um, sure.
Why didn't you say so?
Follow me.
And mind
the pterodactyl droppings.
But if you
get some on you, rub it in.
It's just like lotion.
Huh?
I will never leave you.
No matter what.
Huh?
Hey!
Fred?
- Shaggy?
- Fred!
Shaggy!
Wait, how'd you get here?
Where are Daphne and Velma?
Dastardly kidnapped us
and was holding us captive
on his super awesome airship.
Jeez, that thing is cool.
But never mind that.
Where's Scooby-Doo?
Has he been taken?
No. He's with
his new "hero" friends.
We're on a break.
You've missed a lot.
Shaggy,
Scooby-Doo is in grave danger.
Dastardly's on his way here
right now,
and he won't stop
until he gets him.
Dastardly?
We can't let that happen.
Exactly!
Now, take me to Scooby-Doo.
As it turns out,
I wasn't even
the velociraptor's father.
Anyhoo, there it is.
The slaghoople.
Brian, we found the last skull.
Mission accomplished.
Now, if you would give us
a hand carrying it out,
we'll take it back to our jet.
Uh-uh-uh.
The only way
to take the slaghoople
is to defeat the protector
in battle.
And that's me.
You?
Scooby, this is it.
It's my hero moment.
I can totally pound the crap
out of this little guy.
Doesn't sound heroic.
Hey, you're on,
but I think you're gonna need
a few friends.
Oh, I've got friends.
And they do like a good show.
All right now.
Let's get our fight on!
Come at me, little man.
Little?
Did you just call me little?
No. He said big.
I did call you little,
pipsqueak.
He said big squeak.
You can call me...
Captain Caveman!
I know I'm small.
It's a pituitary thing.
Are you not entertained?
Brian! Come on.
Dynomutt is right.
I'm not my dad.
Scooby, help!
What do I do?
Use the suit thingies.
Who's your captain?
Captain Caveman!
Hoorah!
Huh?
Huh. Hey.
Wow, you're doing great.
I almost hate
to do this to you.
Spin it to win it.
I want my Raggy!
Oh!
You make a break for the skull.
I'll go pick up
Brian and Scooby.
On it.
Leave him alone.
I love a challenge
like I love dinosaur eggs.
Over easy.
- Uh...
- Look out!
Dang, those are
some dope wheels.
Whatever wheels are!
- Scooby!
- Raggy?
- How'd you get here?
- No, let me go first.
- Scoob...
- Where did that
anachronistic van come from?
Fred brought it,
but that's not important.
How'd he get the van
to a prehistoric world
hidden miles beneath
the North Pole?
I don't know.
Why don't you ask Fred...
Who's Fred?
- ...right now, I need to...
- Not me.
Dick Dastardly!
That's right.
Your foolish friend
- led me straight to you.
- Oh, no.
If you will excuse me,
I have a treasure to collect.
Raggy!
Scooby!
Oh, and I almost forgot
to take out the rubbish.
Whoa!
- Whoa, nice catch!
- Ahhh!
- What's up?
- Ta-ta!
See you all in Athens.
Oh! No, you won't.
Because the only way out
is with a jet.
Well, good thing we have one.
Oh, do you now?
There's something
about the way he said,
"Do you?" and then laughed
that makes me think
he did something to our ship.
I hate it when I'm right.
We're lucky
it doesn't happen often.
Ugh.
The primary engine
is destroyed.
The thrusters are intact,
but they're way too small
to launch the ship.
So, we're stuck here?
Well, maybe
if your little buddy
didn't lead the bad guy
right to us...
Leave Shaggy alone.
Yeah, what kind of hero blames
other people for his problems?
Meet Brian.
Hey, you shut your dog face.
You shut your face-face.
Because of you, Scooby-Doo has
a first-class ticket
to the dogpocalypse.
Don't you point
your finger at me.
Well, don't double-point
Maybe I'll triple-finger point
at you.
Then obviously I'm gonna
quadruple-finger point at you.
Ha! That's just a wave,
dipstick.
Hey, get off of him.
He's the one that started it!
Toxic masculinity.
Stop! Stop it, all of you!
It's my fault. I'm to blame.
I let my own jealousy
break me and Scooby up.
I was afraid that with his
new suit and his new team,
things were gonna change.
And they did change.
But, like, that's okay.
People can grow.
But it doesn't mean
that we're growing apart.
Because the one thing
that will never change
is that Scooby-Doo
is my best friend.
Ten years ago,
a little boy made a promise
to a stray puppy
that he'd never leave him,
no matter what.
And I'm gonna keep
that promise.
Now, it's time we stop
this mustachioed menace
from opening the gates
to the underpass...
- Underworld.
- And letting loose
the fearsome sippy-cup.
- Cerberus.
- So, what do you say
- we get out of Middle-earth...
- Copyright infringement.
...and go get
my always-snacking,
never-lacking,
often-napping dog back!
Who's with me?
We are!
Let's do this.
Hey!
That one! Thank you!
Momma!
Dad! What is that thing?
Oh, I've waited!
I've waited and waited
for this very moment!
Give me your paw.
- No!
- What?
Back again like a bad oyster.
Guys, supernatural
transformation dead ahead.
I thought
you mewling millennials
were done for good!
Destroy those falcon fools!
- Yes!
- No!
Whoa!
No!
I told you, you were the most
important dog in the world.
Now let me show you why.
And the slipper fits.
It's happening!
It's finally happening!
Uh-oh.
Little more than
I bargained for.
If I were you, I'd run!
Monster!
Hurry! Daddy!
You guys are alive!
Scooby-Doo!
Scooby!
Yoo-hoo!
Oh, thank goodness! The gang's
finally back together.
- Buddy, I never meant to...
- I know. Me neither.
All right.
Time to take that 3-headed
hound down to the pound.
Is everyone accounted for?
Whew. Well, that was
my cardio for the day.
Dynomutt, you saved us.
Yeah, thank you!
Yes, Dynomutt!
At long last, my treasure!
Oh, no.
I'm too late.
I've been searching for years,
my friend.
But I didn't make it in time.
I'm sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
There are so many things
we never got to do together.
Huh?
You're alive?
You're alive!
You cantankerous canine,
how could you do that to me?
Rasm-Frasm.
Stop! I'm not joking! Stop!
Oh! I...
I can't stay mad.
You're alive!
So, that's Cerberus.
We've got to stop him
before he gets into the city.
Like, how?
We fight monsters
all the time.
Remember the phantom sea squid
at the haunted aquarium?
That was
a real estate developer
with a couple of flashlights
and a sound effects machine.
This is the real deal.
Right, Fred?
Fred?
Where's Fred?
You shall be avenged.
For the Mystery Machine!
He's just attacking.
I mean, are we supposed
to be attacking?
Huh?
- Fred!
- Come on. Hurry! Run!
Sorry, gang. Never mess
with another man's vehicle.
We need a plan.
Okay, like, Velma and Fred,
you get to the gate
and, uh, figure out
how to close it.
And we'll distract Cerberus.
Great idea, guys.
That was awesome!
Smart.
Yeah,
we've been through a lot.
We've grown.
Brian!
Go! Go, go, go, go, go!
Now, Velma!
Let's go!
What do we do?
Maybe he wants a Scooby Snack?
I don't have any Scooby Snacks.
I always have a spare.
Sorry.
And that's why
I always have a spare spare.
Scooby!
I'm so weak.
Nice doggy.
I got this.
Look out!
Are you okay, little guy?
Brian, what are you
doing back here?
I'm calling my dad.
Hey!
You don't need your dad.
Yes, I do, all right?
He's the hero.
I'm not. I can't win this.
So what?
Look at Scooby and Shaggy!
They're terrified, and they're
taking on Cerberus!
I'm terrified!
Why are we
taking on Cerberus?
Well, in their own unique way.
So you're saying it's heroic
to be scared,
and even to lose sometimes?
Dude, this is it!
This is my hero moment,
my real hero moment.
And it's my moment, too.
My job is to have your back.
So what do you say,
Blue Falcon?
Okay, now I'm crying.
- Dyno!
- Help!
Scooby and Shaggy
are about to be puppy chow.
It's time for you
to spread your wings and fly.
You're right.
This suit just makes me a hero
on the outside.
It's time to tap
into the hero. In here.
You know your suit has actual
wings and can fly, right?
Oh, right. The wings!
Let's do this!
I got a little too excited
on the takeoff.
This way, Scooby-Doo!
Oh, Cerberus.
Here, poochie-boy.
This superhero stuff is fun!
Whoa!
Scooby!
- I got you.
- Ooh.
Farewell, fools!
Sayonara, suckers!
Dastardly!
We're rich!
Rasm-Frasm. Money bath!
Aw. He got his friend back.
Daphne, focus.
I wish I had that
clue from Dastardly's ship.
You mean this thing?
Are you telling me
you had that the whole time?
Better late than never!
This is awesome!
Oh, good.
They got him distracted.
Hey, little guy.
Remember at the bowling alley
when you transformed
into that thing?
No. No, no, no.
Not that scary thing.
Huh.
Looks like a riddle.
Or a prophecy?
"Two brothers
bridge the earthly void.
One man, one dog.
The key employed."
"One to open, two to close,
a pair whose friendship
forever grows."
That's it! It takes
one to open but two to lock.
Okay.
Before the creepy scorpion
but after the scary pin.
Yeah. Yeah, that's it!
But there's a catch.
Incoming! We've gotta get
Cerberus closer to the gate!
On it!
Here, doggy, doggy, doggy.
Man, looks like
we just spared the world!
Bowling puns.
This is so us.
Okay, so how do we lock
that puppy up?
What?
One of you has to hold
the gates shut here...
While one of you locks them
from inside the Underworld.
What? No!
There has to be another way.
Right, Velma?
Alexander the Great
built these gates
to be locked only by him
and his dog Peritas.
As the last descendant
of Peritas,
Scooby has to do it.
But the prophecy says he needs
his best friend to help him.
That's you, Shaggy.
There's no other way.
I'm the key.
I'll go.
It says one of us
had to be on the inside,
but it doesn't say which one.
No!
Buddy, back when we were kids,
you saved me.
Now it's my turn.
No. Don't. Raggy, wait!
No!
Raggy.
Scoob. You're the best friend
I could ever ask for.
And you always will be.
Raggy.
Are we missing something?
"A pair whose friendship
forever grows."
Could it mean something else?
I think it means that
Scoob and Shaggy's friendship
will live on whether
they're together or not.
But...
...why would
Alexander make a gate
that would separate him
from his best friend forever?
He must have built a way out.
Uh... Guys.
It's Alexander the Great.
Look at this inscription.
It's a message from him.
"Our bond
will never break or bend..."
"So, my friend, it's time
to return to your home."
Maybe Scooby
should give it a try.
Raggy, you promised
you'd never leave.
Come home.
Raggy?
Zoinks!
I guess friendship
really did save the day.
Raggy!
Scooby-Doo!
I love you guys!
You gave us
quite a scare, Shaggy.
Well, it takes more
than a 3-headed monster
to keep me away
from my best bud.
Tank, empath, brain.
I finally figured out
what you guys are.
You're the heart
of Mystery, Inc.
Ow, ow, oh. Ow!
Sorry. Metal tongue.
Shoulda thought that through.
Put me down,
you traitorous tin cans!
Rasm-Frasm. Stupid robots.
Time to pay for your crimes,
Dick Dastardly.
Or is it?
Simon Cowell?
Wow, that is
a solid impersonation.
Thank you.
I also played Rum Tum Tugger
in my secondary school's
production of Cats.
This makes no sense.
How could he have time to judge
the world's
greatest talent shows
and build a giant airship?
Dick Dastardly?
Drat. No one ever goes
for the double unmasking.
You are coming with us.
I would've gotten away with it
if it weren't for you
mismatched meddling miscreants!
Congratulations, you two.
You just saved the world.
How do you feel?
Hungry.
Oh, man. It's perfect.
Wait, Shaggy,
where's the DJ you hired?
Like, they'll be here
any minute.
"They"?
Surprise!
You know we wouldn't
miss your grand opening.
DJ Blue Falcon!
And that is how
you make an entrance.
Good job, Keith.
Thank you, BF!
I'm so happy you're back.
You know, I'm proud of him,
but he couldn't have done this
without us.
I know.
I am so gonna need a raise.
Hello?
Hello, Mystery Inc.?
There's been a mysterious
sighting in San Pedro.
Residents report seeing
a phantom tuna trawler
and the ghost
of an old sea captain.
G-g-g-ghost?
Looks like we're on the case.
Let's hit it.
Hey, Dusty!
Watch the shop, please.
What do you say, buddy?
Let's Scooby-Dooby-Doo it!